<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<android.support.constraint.ConstraintLayout xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:app="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    android:background="@drawable/background"

    tools:context=".rules">

    <TextView
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="match_parent"
        android:scrollbars="vertical"
        tools:layout_editor_absoluteX="0dp"
        tools:layout_editor_absoluteY="71dp" />

    <Button
        android:id="@+id/home"
        android:layout_width="wrap_content"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:layout_marginStart="135dp"
        android:layout_marginLeft="135dp"
        android:layout_marginTop="632dp"
        android:layout_marginEnd="135dp"
        android:layout_marginRight="135dp"
        android:layout_marginBottom="51dp"
        android:onClick="mainActivity"
        android:text="return to home"
        app:layout_constraintBottom_toBottomOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintEnd_toEndOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintStart_toStartOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintTop_toTopOf="parent" />

    <TextView
        android:id="@+id/textView2"
        android:layout_width="332dp"
        android:layout_height="480dp"
        android:text="The playing: Set Up Starting the game Repeat the following until one team as 10 or more points: Deal Call Trump Play the round Play trick (5x) The first team to 10 points wins!   Set Up To play this game, you will need a standard deck of cards.  However, the only cards used for this game are the 9, 10, Jack, Queen, King and Ace of each suit. This game is played with four people.  You, your AI partner, and two AI’s playing against you.   The game starting the game: Start the game by dealing out the deck with cards face up.  The first person to receive a black jack will be the first dealer   Dealing: The dealer will deal 5 cards to each player in 2 cycles, dealing either 3 or 2 cards to each player. Each player may look at their cards as soon as they receive them. After this, there will be 4 cards remaining.  These cards will be called the kiddy.  The dealer will place the kiddy face down in front of them and flip over the top card.  This card will be referred to as the “card turned up”   Call Trump: There are two rounds when calling trump. In the first round, each player (starting to the right of the dealer) decides if they want the suit of the turned up card to be trump. If yes, the player will say “pick it up!”  If the player says “pick it up!” the dealer will put the turned up card into their hand and put one card from their hand face down into the kiddy.  The kiddy is then put off to the side.  Then playing the round begins. If the player says “pass” then nothing happens, and the next player will decided if they want the dealer to pick up the card turned up or pass. If all four players pass on the card turned up, the dealer will flip over the card turned up, and put the kiddy off to the side. Then, each player (starting to the left of the dealer) will either pass or call trump. To call trump, the player will just say the name of the suit they want trump to be.  There is one caveat however: you cannot call say the suit of the card turned up.  Your chance for that suit to be trump has passed! If the player says “pass” nothing happens and the next player may either call trump or pass. In the second round, the dealer cannot pass.  They must pick a suit for trump.  Sometimes, the dealer has a very bad hand and will not want to call trump, but still has to.  For this reason, this rule is often called “screw the dealer!”   Playing the round: The player to the left of the dealer leads the first trick (we will cover what lead and trick means later). Then, the winner of each previous trick will lead the next trick. Once all five tricks are played, points will be awarded in the following way: If the team that calls trump wins all 5 tricks, that team is awarded 2 points. If the team that calls trump wins exactly 3 or exactly 4 of the five tricks, that team is awarded 1 point. If the team that did not call trump wins 3 or more of the 5 tricks, that team is awarded two points.  This situation is called a “Euchre!” and can be very embarrassing for the team that called trump. Note to the player:  A “round” is usually just called a “hand” by most Euchre players.  We decided to call it a “round” so we wouldn’t get confused when developing.   Playing a Trick: The “trick” is simply a word for the most basic unit of game play. The “lead” is the player in each trick who plays the first card. To start the trick, the lead plays a card face up in front of them.   Then, the player to their right also places a card face up in front of them. Step 4 repeats two more times until all 4 players have played a card. There is one caveat for the three players who are not the lead:  If they have cards (one or more) in their hand that are the same suit as the card played by the lead they must play one of those cards.   Deciding the winner of the Trick: Figuring out who wins each trick (and who is winning while the play of each trick is in progress) is perhaps the strangest and most difficult part of the game for new players.  However, after playing some tricks and paying close attention, this aspect of the game begins to make sense very quickly. A card that is not the same suit as trump will be called “off suit” The easiest situation to understand is when trump is played.  In this case, the player that plays the highest trump card wins the trick. If trump is not played, then the highest card (what we mean by “highest” will be explained in the next section) that is the same suit as the one played by the lead wins the trick.  That is, the player who played that card wins that trick.   Values of the off suit cards (ie, what we mean when we say “highest”): The values that the off suit cards take on are exactly what a new player might expect. The ace has the highest value for each off suit, followed by the king, then the queen, jack*, 10 and 9.  Values of the trump cards: This might be the other difficult and strange aspect of the game for new players.  Recall that “trump” just means a particular suit. The highest valued trump is the jack of trump.  This is called the “right bower” The second highest valued trump card is the jack of the suit that is the same color as trump.  This is called the “left bower”.  This card is NOT considered to be the suit that it has printed on it.  Instead, this card becomes whatever suit trump is for game playing purposes (eg, following the lead’s suit)  So always be careful when you have this card in your hand to make sure you are actually following the suit played by the lead.  So for example, if spades is trump the right bower is the jack of spaced, and the left bower is the jack of clubs. Also, the jack of clubs is not a club card.  It is a spade in this round.  So if they lead plays a queen of clubs, and you have the jack of clubs and the 9 of clubs, you cannot play your jack! After this, the value of the suits decreases as expected.  Putting it all together, the highest to lowest valued trump cards are: Right bower, Left bower, Ace, King, Queen, 10, 9.   Another note on deciding the winner of each trick: According to the rules on values of cards, we could rephrase the rules for deciding the winner of each trick as follows: All trump cards have higher values than all off suit cards. The card played with the highest value wins.  If no trump is played, the highest card of the suit that matches the lead’s card wins.   Going Alone: There is one more aspect of the game that occasionally comes into  play. During the “calling trump” portion of the game, if a player is confident that they have a very strong hand they have a third option (other than “pass” and “pick it up”).  The player may also say “I’m going alone.” Saying “I’m going alone” works almost exactly the same as “pick it up” except, the player’s partner puts their hand face down and sits out for that round. Scoring is very slightly different: If the player who is going alone wins all 5 tricks, that team will be awarded 4 points! The other rules scoring are exactly the same.  So if the player wins 3 or 4 of the 5 tricks, they are awarded 1 point.   If that player wins less than 3 of the 5 tricks, the other team wins 2 points. "
        android:textColor="#F4F2F2"
        app:layout_constraintBottom_toBottomOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintEnd_toEndOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintHorizontal_bias="0.493"
        app:layout_constraintStart_toStartOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintTop_toTopOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintVertical_bias="0.43" />
</android.support.constraint.ConstraintLayout>